MICHAEL THORDSON

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Successful at completing new installations, updates, and configuration of network components. Experienced in setting up devices, troubleshooting issues and optimizing settings. Knowledgeable about maintaining current software and hardware to meet user needs.

WORK HISTORY

NETWORK INTEGRATIONS TECHNICIAN , 08/2020 to 02/2021 Insight Global Assigned To Vision Technology Inc. - Las Vegas, United States

Performed configuration, installation, troubleshooting, and repair of 5520 Cisco Wireless Lan Controllers, ICX7450-48P-E, and ICX 6430-C12 Brocade network switches and devices for the Clark County School District. Large-scale deployments include WIFI solutions, VOIP handsets, server upgrades, Cisco AIR-AP 3802I Wireless Access Points, cable and fiber management, backup power supplies, and other network devices.

Network Technician, 04/2018 to 03/2020

TEKsystems Inc. - Las Vegas, NV

Assigned to the Las Vegas Festival Grounds to perform configuration of Cisco 3850 Catalyst switches and Cisco 3702E Wireless Access Points with the lead network engineer for the extension of the existing network for such events as: iHeart Music Festival, AWS Intersec Music Festival, and CONEXPO-CON/AGG 2020. Also participate in a property-wide network LAN device refresh project at Mirage, Bellagio Hotel, and Casino as well as the Cosmopolitan of Las Vegas.

Installation & de-installation of cabling cross-connects and maintenance of network devices, related network devices, infrastructure, and related procedures adhere to organizational values. Hands-on with customers who are experiencing connection issues with their network devices (Phones, Tablets, and PCs). Work with 2nd level support network-related issues with both Wi-Fi, Fiber Optic, UTP, STP, etc. Cabling. Install, terminate, maintain, and troubleshoot network cabling infrastructure including moves, add-ons, and changes of any network or related equipment.

CONTACT

Address: Las Vegas, NV 89148

Phone: 7025101700

Email: mikethordson@gmail.com

SKILLS

- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate
- · · Layer 2 port security experience
- · 802.1x experience
- · Routing protocol expertise
- Cisco Catalyst configuration experience
- · Active Directory Knowledge
- VLAN/Trunking aggregation
- · Linux/Network Automation
- · · Technical infrastructure upgrades
- QoS/CoS expertise
- Cisco configuration experience
- Networking and routing protocol expertise
- · Python experience
- · Wireshark experience
- Excellent customer service skills and interpersonal skills to effectively communicate

Fluent with the following test equipment: Corning Fusion Splicer, Fluke OTDR, Fluke DTX1800, Fluke, Fluke Link Runner Pro, etc. Edge network equipment, Core network equipment, and Serial-to-IP devices, both copper and fiber.

Package Handler/Driver, 11/2016 to 04/2018 United Parcel Service Inc - Maple Grove, MN

As a package handler and driver, obey traffic laws and follow established traffic and transportation procedures. Responsible for bills and receipts, collect payments for goods delivered and loaded and verify the contents of inventory. Maintained records, such as vehicle logs, records of cargo, or billing statements, following regulations, complete pre-and post-trip safety inspections, recording and reporting any defects and malfunctions. Practice safe and secure loading methods to avoid damaging goods, work overnight shifts during peak periods.

Pest Control Technician, 06/2015 to 11/2016 Alterra, Eco Gen, Terminix - Las Vegas, NV

Provided free home inspections to potential clients to increase company exposure and business leads. Responded to customer phone calls and emails quickly to maximize service and improve retention rates. Adhered to the most stringent safety procedures when applying chemicals to ensure the health of others.

Contractor, 09/2012 to 06/2015

Filtrex - Las Vegas, NV

Installed smart thermostat into Sprint retail stores. Monitored network performance and provided network performance statistical reports for both real-time and historical measurements. Established compatibility with third-party software products by developing a program for modification and integration. Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders. Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of product or service. Recommended architectural improvements, design solutions and integration solutions. Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.

CERTIFICATIONS

- · CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate
- CCNP ENCOR Cisco Certified Network Professional (in progress)

EDUCATION

Associate of Applied Science, Computer Networking Systems ITT Technical Institute - Henderson, NV

U.S. NAVY

U.S.S Mobile Bay CG-53

Torpedoman's Mate | Yokosuka, Japan

Honorably Discharged after completion of service